

Andrew M. Kent

Curriculum Vitae

Research Interests

My research interests revolve around programming language concepts which increase the productivity and effectiveness of software developers. I am particularly interested in increasing the accessibility and effectiveness of formal verification techniques by exploring their gradual application in real world software.

Education

2014-Present Computer Science PhD Student, Indiana University, Bloomington, IN.

Topic: Gradual Dependent Typing

2010–2014 BS Computer Science, Brigham Young University, Provo, UT.

Graduated magna cum laude (8/2013), began graduate studies.

Experience

Research

2014-Present Graduate Research Assistant, Indiana University, Bloomington, IN.

Conducting research in gradual typing, evaluating applications in mainstream languages and extensions involving dependent types.

Advisor: Sam Tobin-Hochstadt

2013–2014 Graduate Research Assistant, Brigham Young University, Provo, UT.

Investigated the formalization of security protocol analysis techniques (Strand Spaces) utilizing the Coq proof assistant to create a verified basis for accessible, automated protocol analysis techniques.

Advisor: Dr. Jay McCarthy.

2011 Undergraduate Research Assistant, Brigham Young University, Provo, UT.

Developed method for automatically generating a historical social network from source documents (e.g. journals) to aid historical research.

Advisors: Dr. William Berrett and Dr. Tom Sederberg.

Industry

2012 **Software Development Engineer Intern**, *Microsoft Corporation*, Redmond, WA. Explored optimizations and improvements for Microsoft OneNote during a summer internship, receiving a full-time offer for employment upon completion.

2005–2010 Signals Intelligence Analyst, U.S. Marine Corps, Camp Pendleton, CA.

Provided detailed signals intelligence analysis and reporting in support combat operations in the Al Anbar province of Iraq during two separate deployments. Additionally, trained and led a team of six signals intelligence analysts during the second deployment.

Teaching

2013 Teaching Assistant, Brigham Young University, Provo, UT.

Undergraduate Course: Programming Language Design

Helped students seeking assistance with concepts and assignments and assisted in teaching on several occasions.

Publications

- 2014 **Design and Evaluation of Gradual Typing in Python**, with Michael M. Vitousek, Jeremy G. Siek, and Jim Baker. In the *Proceedings of the 10th ACM Symposium on Dynamic Languages* (DLS '14).
- 2011 Linking the Past: Discovering Historical Social Networks from Documents and Linking to a Genealogical Database, with Douglas J. Kennard William A. Barrett. In the *Proceedings of the 2011 Workshop on Historical Document Imaging and Processing* (HIP '11).

Awards

- Awarded NASA Space Grant Consortium Fellowship (Fall 2013 Winter 2014)
- Top graduate in multi-service military Intermediate Communications Signals Analysis course (Corry Station, FL, Apr – Aug 2007)

Community

2014-Present Cub Master, Boy Scouts of America, Bloomington, IN.

Helped organize combined scouting activities for youth ages 8-11.

2013–2014 Assistant Webelos Den Leader, Boy Scouts of America, Provo, UT.

Organized and ran scouting activities for youth ages 10-11.

2011–2012 Family History and Genealogy Consultant, LDS Church, Provo, UT.

Taught classes and helped local community members conduct family history and genealogy.

Additional Information

- U.S. Department of Defense TS/SCI Clearance (expired 2011)
- Eagle Scout